

Stephen McGregor

Technical writer



Kapiti Coast, New Zealand



+64 0204 135 2650



github.com/AbsurdMagpieScrutinies



work@stephen-mcgregor.com

About me ——

Friendly, clever, educated. Stephen collects information, history books, music and GNU/Linux documentation while trying to watch only the best cinema. Nearly every day he'll spend a couple of hours programing or messing with his Debian GNU/Linux setup. Stephen has sung in many many choirs and, since starting to listen to audiobooks, reads (that is listens to) up to six each month. Living in Istanbul for most of the last eight years he's now, finally, returning home.

Skills

I.T. general knowledge

technical writing

writing aesthetics

Perl

C++

0 1 1

Python

Interests

Complicated systems, taking notes, bringing order to chaos, opportunities.

Experience

2014-17	Proofreading, Editing @ multiple clients & nationalities) editing
	Stephen set up a small business, found clients and companies, and
	complied with their deadlines, style guides, and invoicing policies.
	Technical: manuals, academic papers, many IT docs, technical web-
	sites, contracts, chemical publications. Non-technical: corporate
	publicity, trade-show documentation, governmental statements &
	reports, brochures, personnel reports. See my work list here.

2013 Technical Writer (contractor) @ Contact Energy SAP Migration Collected documents and unwritten wisdom from SMEs. Produced parts of the required specifications for a major SAP migration.

2010-13 Proofreading, Editing @ multiple clients & nationalities editing See 2014-17.

2008-10 English Teacher @ Istanbul, Turkey English Taught classes & private students, generated course materials.

2008 Technical Writer @ Country Energy (Australia) systems migration Documented a set of major upgrades and virtualizations.

2007-08 Technical Writer @ Alcatel-Lucent telco
In a team, documented a small subset of Alcatel-Lucent's telecommunication hardware and processes. Worked on a New Zealand-wide telephone system replacement, the installation of VoIP and other IP services.

2007 C++ Developer @ NZ Racing Board (The TAB) GUI
Developed a GUI (touch-screen) for the TAB's point-of-sale computers. C++ on Fedora Linux in a Qt environment, plus Perl (tests).

2006-07 Technical Writer @ EDS/Telecom NZ telco WebSphere, Genesys IVR system, VoiceXML voice-recognition.

2005-05 Embedded Developer @ MAS Zengrange embedded & telco Assembly & C development, including IC and GPS chip drivers.

2002-03 Technical Writer @ Link Communications (Australia) telco Wrote 600-page manual for continent-wide telco system (C).

Technical Writer @ National Bank NZ bond trading

Bond-trading systems' (C++) as-builts and system diagrams.

1998-2000 C++ Developer & B.A. @ Quality Systems C++, ERP Coded & helped design a trade discounts & rebates ERP module.

1996-98 Network Analyst, Quality Mgr @ Enerco NZ networks Network, economic modelling, quality manuals, analyses, auditing.

earlier computer operator; steel mill analyst; computer lab supervisor; AI researcher; sas programmer; research assistant; statistics tutor;

gold-mine lab worker; entrepreneur; market researcher; antiques restorer; statistical analyst; barman; metalworker.

Education

2001

2005	post-grad electronic physics electronic physics, geomagnetism, filters, DSP, fib	Victoria University re optics
2004	post-grad diploma advanced international marketing, tourism, third-	Otago University world marketing
2003	graduate diploma electronic design and systems, microcontrollers, p	Otago University ohysics
1993	B.Sc (Chemistry) chemical engineering, organic chemistry, bio-tech	Otago University , pharmacology
1990	B.Com (Marketing)	Otago University

market research / international marketing



Stephen McGregor

Technical writer



Kapiti Coast, New Zealand



+64 0204 135 2650



github.com/AbsurdMagpieScrutinies



work @ stephen-mcgregor.com

About me ——

Friendly, clever, educated. Stephen collects information, history books, music and GNU/Linux documentation while trying to watch only the best cinema. Nearly every day he'll spend a couple of hours programing or messing with his Debian GNU/Linux setup. Stephen has sung in many many choirs and, since starting to listen to audiobooks, reads (that is listens to) up to six each month. Living in Istanbul for most of the last eight years he's now, finally, returning home.

I.T. general knowledge technical writing writing aesthetics

Perl

C++

Python

Skills

Embedded

Tech writing Since 2001, mostly manuals for telecommunications & IT. Also

APIs, as-builts and banking. A collector & reader of style guides.

Editing Proofread and edited thousands of commercial, technical, IT, legal

and miscellaneous documents. Broad range of clients.

Telecoms Professionally developed a telecoms device. Documented many

different telecoms systems. Studied fibre optics at post-grad level.

A qualified and experienced embedded developer. Used dsPic, Atmel & FPGAs. Grad Dip(Electronics) and studied post-grad.

Coding Perl 5, C, Python, C++, assembly. Formerly SAS, SPSS. Coding

since 1983 and still coding most days. My Github is here.

Applications Microsoft Office, Inkscape, Visio, Gimp (like Photoshop). Vim. Tra-

dos Studio, Wordfast. Have used MadCap Flare, Adobe InDesign.

Platforms Unix since 1989, Debian GNU/Linux since 2001, Microsoft since

MS-DOS. My first computer was a ZX-81.

Database MySQL, sqlite3, some Oracle. Intermediate-level SQL but very

familiar with databases. Many database-orientated roles.

Commercial Telecoms, heavy industry, finance, defense, utilities, software.

Started own small business. Two business degrees.

Modeling Modeling for a \$35m capacity purchase, a \$10m economic project

and a \$20m legal case. Capacity reporting for Telecom NZ.

Sys Admin Networking, wireless, iptables, security & encryption, udev and

/sys, /proc, kernel stuff, sound and video formats, backups, logs.

Statistical Was a statistical analyst; studied statistics to uni second-year.

Analytical National Network Analyst, BA. An analytical, technical disposition.

[Samples]

My brochure is here and my creative CV here. These and more on github.

A System Manual I wrote is here and an API, Dev Guide is here. A sample System Guide can viewed here and an IVR / voice recognition as-built I wrote is here. Many examples of my editing and Proofreading can be downloaded from here.

A few of my infoviz Visios can be seen here and an art-piece in UML (yes) is here.

How it is

I am all about tech and writing, programming and taking notes. I am doing exactly this most of the day, most days, anyway, so I might as well be helping you or your client. Just look at my experience. I've worked in or with most industries and businesses and I'm familiar with most technical domains.

So, maybe you want to hire someone else? Well, I've dealt with a few technical writers in my time and *every single one* has, both, written poorly *and* has had neither any feeling for, nor any real understand of, technology. For example, you have been sent a pile of Microsoft Word CVs full of "strategized leveraged convergence" and "facilitated next-generation methodologies". Meanwhile, I learnt latex (MTEX) from scratch to make this CV, and there's not one overly vague participle or emotional adjective to be found in it. The choice is simple: either me, or one of them. I know who I'd choose.